Praveensankar M

M.Tech - Student



praveensankar1995@gmail.com Homepage: https://praveen.xyz/

Google Scholar:

https://scholar.google.co.in/citations?user=o

yTr15UAAAAJ&hl=en&authuser=1

ORCID:

https://orcid.org/0000-0003-3614-5722

BIO

I am a PhD Research Fellow working on Blockchain and Privacy in the ND research Group at the University of Oslo, Norway. I have completed M.Tech. in Computer Science and Engineering at the National Institute of Technology Puducherry, India and B.E. in Computer Science and Engineering at PSG College of Technology, Coimbatore, India. I have research experience in Blockchain, Named Data Networking and Lattice Cryptography. I have developed an e-bidding system on the hyperledger fabric blockchain network. I have developed an Intrusion Detection System for NDN based VANETs. I have developed an authenticated encryption scheme based on lattice cryptography. My research interests are in Blockchain, Cryptography, Lattice Cryptography and Network Security.

Area of Interest

- Blockchain
- Privacy and Security
- Network Security

Cryptography

EDUCATION

PhD. - Blockchain and Privacy

Department of Informatics, University of Oslo, Norway. October 2020 - Present

M.Tech. - Computer Science and Engineering

National Institute of Technology Puducherry, Karaikal July 2018 - June 2020

CGPA - 9.82 / 10 (Class Topper)

B.E. - Computer Science and Engineering

PSG College of Technology, Coimbatore July 2012 - May 2016 CGPA - 7.69 / 10

PUBLICATIONS

Conference

 P. Manimaran and A. R. K. P, "NDNIDS: An Intrusion Detection System for NDN Based VANET," 2020 IEEE 91st Vehicular Technology Conference (VTC2020-Spring), Antwerp, Belgium, 2020, pp. 1-5, doi: 10.1109/VTC2020-Spring48590.2020.9129365.

https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9129365

 P. Manimaran and R. Dhanalakshmi, "Blockchain-Based Smart Contract for E-Bidding System," 2019 2nd International Conference on Intelligent Communication and Computational Techniques (ICCT), Jaipur, India, 2019, pp. 55-59.

doi: 10.1109/ICCT46177.2019.8969042.

https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8969042

Book Chapter

 Ravi, Chandrasekar and Praveensankar Manimaran. "Introduction of Blockchain and Usage of Blockchain in Internet of Things." *Transforming Businesses With Bitcoin Mining and Blockchain Applications*. IGI Global, 2020. 1-15. Web. 18 Oct. 2019. doi:10.4018/978-1-7998-0186-3.ch001

https://www.igi-global.com/chapter/introduction-of-blockchain-and-usage-of-blockchain-in-internet-of-things/238356

EXPERIENCE

PhD Research Fellow

University of Oslo, Norway October 2020 - Present

- Investigating the possibilities of introducing Privacy in Blockchain
- Project: SmartMed (https://www.smartmed.no/)
- Research Group: Networks and Distributed Systems (ND) group
- Supervisor: Roman Vitenberg (http://heim.ifi.uio.no/~romanvi/)
- Co-supervisor: Narasimha Veeraraghavan (profile)

Summer Research Intern

National Institute of Technology Calicut, Kozhikode

May 2019 - July 2019

- Studied about Software Defined Networking and experimented mininet simulator
- Studied the architecture of the Named Data Networking and usage of NDN in VANET
- Designed and developed Intrusion Detection System for NDN Based VANET

Software Engineer

Accolite Software India Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore

July 2016 - March 2017

- Worked on the web development
- Language C#, Javascript, Web framework ASP.NET MVC, backend technology -ASP.NET, frontend technology - Jquery and AngularJS, database - Microsoft SQL Server
- Developed POC application for IT Resource Management
- Worked on web development for British Telecommunications through Accolite

Software Engineer Intern

Accolite Software India Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore January 2016 - April 2016

- Worked on the web development
- Language C#, Javascript, Web framework ASP.NET MVC, backend technology -ASP.NET, frontend technology - Jquery and AngularJS, database - Microsoft SQL Server
- Learned about web development in general and studied ASP.NET and Basic javascript for developing websites
- Studied about 3 Layer architecture in ASP.NET

Projects

Android Application for alarm system

PSG College of Technology, Coimbatore

June 2015 - October 2015

- In this application to stop the alarm, the user has to solve either a mathematical puzzle or a logical puzzle or count the number of objects in the image or click the given color in the grid of colors. These functionalities are provided along with traditional alarm functionalities
- Github: https://github.com/praveensankar/Alarm-App

Face Recognition system using Principal Component Analysis

PSG College of Technology, Coimbatore

June 2014 - October 2014

 To detect and recognize an image from a predefined collection of images using the eigenface-based facial recognition • Github: https://github.com/praveensankar/face_recognition

Teaching

1. Teaching Assistant - CS609 Network Programming Lab

National Institute of Technology Puducherry, Karaikal August 2019 - November 2019

2. Teaching Assistant - CS102 Basics of Programming Lab

National Institute of Technology Puducherry, Karaikal January 2019 - April 2019

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C, Python, SQL

Operating Systems: Ubuntu, Windows

Frameworks: Django

Tools: Latex

Achievements

- Scored 96.03 Percentile in Computer Science, GATE 2018
- Scored 98.02% in HSC exam, 2012
- Scored Centum in Computer Science, HSC exam, 2012
- Scored 97.80% in SSLC exam, 2010
- Scored Centum in Maths and Science, SSLC exam, 2010

References

- 1. Dr. G. Aghila, Professor in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at the National Institute of Technology Puducherry, India. **Email**: aghila@nitpy.ac.in
- 2. Dr. R. Dhanalakshmi, Associate Professor in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at the Indian Institute of Information Technology Tiruchirapalli, India. **Email:** dhanalakshmiparthiban@gmail.com
- 3. Dr. P. Arun Raj Kumar, Assistant Professor in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at the National Institute of Technology Calicut, India. **Email:** park@nitc.ac.in